

SOFIANE BEKKARI

IT Web Development & UI/UX Designer

I am an IT professional computer science for more than 5 years in the field. networking, system, programming, web development Front-end, design and some Back-end, DevOps, and programmability with dev tools Python, JSON, XML, APIs, Ansible, I have the ability to learn new concepts and technologies in a short span time with an open team spirit.

: Algérie , Sidi-Bel-Abbes

S: +213 552 85 22 44

in: /Sofiane-bekkari

: /Sofiane-Bekkari

: https://sofiane-portfolio.netlify.app/

SKILLS

- Programming
- DevOps & Deployment
- WEB Development
- Python3
- Flask framwork
- **JavaScript**
- Desing, Figma, UX /UI
- HTML5, CSS3, SASS
- cPanel, DNS, FTP
- SSH, HTTPs, APIs,
- Git, CLI, Bash
- PowerShell, Github
- Virtualization
- Windows & Linux
- **Cloud Resources**
- **Network Programmability**
- Networking
- Infrastructure Security
- IGP Routing Protocol
- **Troubleshooting**
- IPV4 and IPV6 Protocol
- **WAN Technologies**

EXPERIENCE

2019-08/2020-09

2016-11/2017-09

IT Freelancer

IT Support & Development Services,

- Build a project, management, troubleshooting, solving technical issues
- Work on small project for the customers business and technical goals

IT Helpdesk | Support

Telecommunication Services, Laghouat, AFlou

- Responsibilities installation and maintenances new software, printers, network issues.
- Solving technical and general issues of the customers

2016-01/2016-04

IT Helpdesk

Schneider Electric, EgyTech, Sidi Bel Abbess

- Responsibilities for installation, maintenance and provision of daily support both hardware and software, network.
- Worked closely with other team members and supporting teams in resolving open issues.



IT Technician

PC-STAR, Sidi Bel Abbess

- Responsibilities for developing and providing support hardware software application, emails, printers and network related issues.
- Responsible for build desktop installing OS and related software hardware installation and maintenances.

CERTIFICATION

2018-12



Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician (CCENT) ID CSC013383099

2019-06 2019-09



Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA R&S) Routing&Switching ID CSC013383099

2020-06



Juniper Networks Certified Associate, DevOps (JNCIA-DevOps) ID JPR00286698

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2020 Certified Associate ID 2629764190CIBF2020-F

2020-07 Microsoft



Microsoft Certified Azure Cloud Fundamentals ID H475-0088

EDUCATION

2019-08/2019-12

Udacity

Full-Stack Development Track - One Million Arab Coders

- Part 1 Basics and fundamental of HTML5, Css3 build a final project
- Part 2 Fundamental of Python3 Data structure, OOP, best practice, common library

2020-02/2020

Harvard University CS50

CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript

- Built and work on project 1 using HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap
- Built the project 2 web apps using Python, Flask, SQL, API, deploy on Heroku
- Design a front-end for an email client that makes API calls to send and receive emails

2017-12/2020

Cisco Networking Academy & Juniper Junos Genuis Computer Networking And Programmability

- Core and infrastructure for computer networking
- TCP/IP, OSI Model, Topologies, Design, Ethernet, DC
- Linux essentials LPIC, Cybersecurity, Python3 essentials PCAP
- Automation, XML, API, NETCONF, JSON, YAML, BASH

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native English : Advanced French: Intermediary German: Elementary

HOBBIES

- II Read a books
- Learn about new technologies
- Play guitar
- Travel